本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
You...
君は…
台本:小伍  翻译:大脸猫 兰樱  校对:小江 mam  片源:Rei  时间轴:和路雪  压制:Coolkid
そんな　まさか…
No, it can not be...
Did you kill Mr. Earl ?!
伯爵様を殺したのはお前か
バルカシオン伯爵は自ら命を絶たれた
Count Barkasion committed suicide.
You're lying!
うそだ
お前は私を欺き続けたばかりか
Not only do you constantly deceived me,
also took away a loved one!
大切な人までも奪った
絶対に許さない
I will never forgive you!
Prince!
殿下
ルシタニアに女の兵士
Female soldier Lyusitanii?
Stay! Do not kill!
待て　殺すな
There is!
はっ
Start up the Gentiles!
放せ　異教徒ども
放せ
Leave!
Chapter XXV
Battle for the Holy Emmanuel castle over.
聖マヌエル城を巡る戦いは終わった
Barkasion graph suicide.
城主バルカシオン伯は自害
Many of the followers of the faith Yaldabaoth too.
イアルダボート神に敬虔な者の多くも後に続き
Leaving only the sick and wounded,
僅かに残った傷病者のみがパルス軍に救出された
Salvation Army Parsis.
Such is the will of the Crown Prince!
王太子殿下の御意である
To release those who have surrendered!
降伏する者は助けよ　武器なき者は殺すな
Do not kill unarmed!
Darjun!
ダリューン
Prince...
殿下
Yes...
Darjun!
ダリューン
Are you okay?
大丈夫か
Prince, I am ashamed to say it,
殿下…　面目ございませぬ
but I was not able to do away with the silver mask.
あの銀仮面　討ち損じてしまいました
Nothing.
かまわぬ
The main thing is that you're okay.
お主が無事なら　それでよい
殿下も
And you, Prince.
Yes, it was over.
ああ
終わったぞ
We took the castle.
マヌエル城は落とした
Under your command, we emerged victorious.
殿下の指揮の下　我々は勝ったのですね
ああ　ありがとう　ダリューン
Yes. Thank Daryun.
Not to relax!
気を抜くな
全室くまなく捜索しろ
Searched every room!
はっ
There is!
While that success, you might say.
ひとまずは…　といったところか
survivors lyusitaniantsev
ルシタニアの生存者　僅かですが　拘束したそうです
a little, but they were taken into custody.
Put in a prison bunk and treat their wounds.
牢に寝床を作り　負傷者を治療してやってくれ
There is!
はっ
あっ…
はい
Yes?
What is about the unit, stormed the gates?
突入部隊の消息は
それが…　まだ誰も
So far ... no one was found.
Clear.
そうか…　ご苦労
Thank you.
アルフリード
Alfrid ...
あ…あれ　ナルサス
TO? Narsus ...
っていうか　私　どうなったの
Wait a minute, what happened to me?
I live?!
生きてる
I live!
What?
何
Nothing. I am glad.
いや…　よかった
少しは心配した？
You're a little worried?
まさか
What are you.
A woman from the clan Zot's so easy to die, right?
ゾット族の女がそうやすやすと死ぬはずなかろうに
まあ　夫より先立つわけにはいかないしね
Yes, I can not die, and to throw her husband.
I do not remember that I became your husband ...
夫であると認めた覚えはないが…
よっと　何ここ
What place?
Warehouse products.
食料庫だ
どうやら食物の搬入口に落ちて　気絶していたようだな
It looks like you fell unconscious wherever they send food.
そっか
Here's how ...
And what are you doing here, Narsus?
でも　ナルサスはどうしてここに
私は最初から糧食の奪取を最優先に考えている
From the beginning I thought the replenishment provisions.
You're from a good family, and worried about the food?
いい家の出なのに　食べ物にこだわるんだね
Even without a weapon, you can fight with your bare hands and mind.
武器がなくても　知恵と素手で戦える
But without food can not go far.
だが食料がなくては　どうにもならないだろ
軍師ってのは　いろいろ考えなきゃいけないんだね
Yeah, the strategist needs to think about everything.
Simple, Jaswant.
すまんな　ジャスワント
子細ない
Do not worry.
ダリューン卿
Mr. Daryun, I am glad you are safe.
あなたが無事でよかった
Surely, prince of the same opinion.
殿下も　ひと安心のはず
No, Prince became stronger.
いや　殿下はたくましくなられた
He himself can handle, if required.
もうお一人でも進んでいける
それにしても　あなたほどの人にこんな手傷を負わせるとは
But still...
To someone so seriously hurt you ...
Silver mask should not be underestimated.
その銀仮面の男　侮れませんね
His fathomless darkness.
ヤツの闇は計り知れぬ　不気味な男だ
Strange and terrible man.
I hear the word fear from the knight in black.
かの黒衣の騎士が随分と弱気なことだ
Mr. Kisvard.
キシュワード殿
If it was not a whim that bastard, I would've been dead.
ヤツの気まぐれがなければ　俺は討たれていた
なぜヤツは　とどめを刺していかなかったのだ
Why did not he dealt the final blow?
It seemed to me that he plays us.
弄んでいるつもりなのだろう
He does not want to win, when the benefit is small.
辛勝はヤツの望むところではないようだ
こしゃくなヤツめ
That's the same jerk!
おいおい
Hey, hey ...
I'm normal.
もう大丈夫だ
These wounds trifle in comparison with the Prince feelings.
こんな傷　殿下のお気持ちを思えばなんともない
いや　ひと仕事終わったあとのフカーはうまい
After a bit of work becomes more delicious wine!
So you were Marzbanom.
お主　マルズバーンであったか
Something like that.
一応な
なるほど
Clear.
Even among Marzbanov there are different people.
マルズバーンにもさまざまなお人がいるものじゃ
さあ　もう一杯
Thus, even by the glass!
Let's drink.
頂こう
You can go.
ここはよい
There is.
はっ
貴様
You!..
一人だけこんな所にしてしまって　すまない
I'm sorry I put you here alone.
Just you have such a temper ...
お主が暴れるからだぞ
So it's true that the Count has committed suicide?
伯爵様が自害したのは本当なのだな
It was just like talking servants.
従者たちの言ったとおりだ
Barkasion Earl was a good man.
バルカシオン伯爵様は立派な方だった
Yes, it was he who put an end to the battle.
ああ　彼がこの戦いを終わらせた
本来　戦いなど向いてない　お優しい方なのだ
In fact, he was a good man, is not made for war.
So, in Peshavarde I met the real you.
ペシャワールで出会ったのが本当の君だったのだな
違う
No! Etoile I, knight serving Barkasionu Count!
私はバルカシオン伯爵に仕える騎士　エトワールだ
You must be hungry.
おなか　すいているだろう
Here stew.
シチューを持ってきたから
なっ　異教徒の施しなど受けられるか
I will never accept charity from the heathen!
もともとここにあった君たちのものだ
It's still your food.
うるさい
Shut up!
And if you think otherwise?
こう考えたらどうだろう
For you this - the food of the enemy.
これは君にとって敵の食べ物だ
So, if you eat it, reduce the enemy's reserves,
なら　これを君が食べれば敵の食料が減り
and it will affect his army.
敵に損害を与えることになる
Is not it a wonderful goal in the battle?
これは立派な武勲じゃないかな
ばかばかしい　そんな詭弁に誰が…
Nonsense! Who will lead to such a trick ...
ああ
Yes. But, at least,
だが少なくとも我が軍にとって　いいことはないのは本当だ
it will not benefit my army.
And it is true. These products are not your prey.
確かに　お前たちの得にはならないな
パンもどうぞ
And the bread.
Maybe you tell your story?
よければ聞かせてくれないか
Why did you decide to become a knight?
なぜ君は騎士になろうと思ったのだ
My real name is Estelle.
私の本名はエステルというが　その名は捨てた
I tossed it.
Why?
なぜ
Estelle - a girl's name!
エステルとは女の名だ
私は騎士の家に養子としてもらわれた
I was adopted by a knight family,
who had no heir.
その家には跡継ぎがいなくてな
So I decided that I should become a knight.
だから　私が騎士となると決めたのだ
それで男になろうと…
And become a man ...
Right! No problems will be, if I'm a guy!
そうだ　私が男なら　なんの問題もない
思い出すな　あのときのことは忘れろ
Enough to remember! Forget about that meeting!
いいな
I got it ?!
Clear. Pity.
そうか　残念だ
なんだと
What ?!
Nothing.
ああ　いや…
もう少しお前たちの食料を減らしてやりたい
I want a little more to reduce your stocks.
A supplement?
おかわりだね
他のものなら　あるから
There are a lot of things.
パルスのアルスラーン王子というヤツは
I heard that Prince Arslan on his head has two curved horns.
２本のねじ曲がった角が生えていると聞いていた
よもや貴様のような坊ちゃんだったとはな
And I could not think that you're just a spoiled kid.
大人になったら　角が生えてくるかもしれない
When he grew up, they can grow.
変わっているな　お前は
You're a strange guy.
I sometimes say that.
時々そう言われる　自分ではよく分からないが
Although he did not notice.
王が王らしくせぬから　パルスは都を奪われる目に遭うのだ
The king did not fulfill his duty,
Parsa here and lost his capital!
王らしく…
Their duty ...
なあ
Say ...
このような戦を避ける方法はないのだろうか
There is a way to avoid this war?
A?
無理な話だ
It's impossible.
As long as you do not stop pochetat all the idols and false gods
お前たちが偶像や邪神を敬うのをやめ　真の神を崇めぬかぎり
and refuse to accept the faith of the true God, we will always fight.
我らは戦い続ける
だから　異教徒は皆殺しにしてもよい…か
therefore
You need to destroy the Gentiles?
そうだ
Right.
I can not agree with it.
私にはとてもそう思えない
なんだと
What?!
Let our philosophy and different,
考え方が違っても　共に暮らすやり方もあるのではないだろうか
Can not we find a way to live together?
そんなものあるはずない
It is simply impossible!
それは…
It!..
君から受け取ったこれを　今日まで何度も読んだ
You gave me this, and I re-read many times.
これは君たちにとっては　すばらしい教えだと思う
I believe that you are the best teachings.
でも
But those who are now in power in Lyusitanii ...
今のルシタニアの権力者たちは
この教えを利用しているだけなのではないか
probably just use this teaching for their own purposes.
Wh-what are you? ..
な…何を
For the sake of their own greed and ambition
自分たちの欲望と野心のために
They hide behind the name of God
神の名を利用して　君たちに殺戮をさせている
and pushing you to kill others.
It makes no sense to kill others because they are pagans!
異教徒だからといって　殺す必要はない
Shut up!
黙れ
Shut up, shut up ...
黙れ　黙れ…
Why do you say that?
なぜそんなことを言うんだ…
Get out! Nothing do not want to hear!
出ていけ　お前と話すことはない
ごめんよ
Simple.
I did not want to teach or judge you.
偉そうに君を責めるつもりはなかった
Etoile.
エトワール
You can read the prayer of faith Yaldabaoth?
君はイアルダボート教の祈りの言葉を唱えられるか
Of course.
当たり前だ
Then pray for the dead tomorrow?
だったら明日　死者に祈りをささげてくれないか
Lyusitaniantsam dead need their prayers, right?
ルシタニアの死者にはルシタニアの祈りが必要だろう
Hey!
私は…
I...
Spoiled ...
あの坊ちゃん…
He specifically?
わざとか
What?
なんだ
This soldier Lyusitanii.
ルシタニアの兵士じゃないか
I see you're still alive.
生きていたか
Comrades who fought with me.
共に戦った同胞たちよ
Followers of the faith Yaldabaoth.
イアルダボートの聖なる信徒たちよ
Be blessed on God's side.
汝らは神のもとに祝福される
魂よ　安らかなれ
Soul Rest in peace.
聖マヌエル城は陥落
Holy Emmanuel Castle fell.
城主バルカシオン伯以下　城内の者はほとんど戦死
Count Barkasion and most died in combat.
アルスラーン率いるパルス軍は
They say the army, led by Arslan,
近日中にも　エクバターナに向けて出立するものと思われます
on any given day can go to Ecbatana.
なんということだ…
How is this possible ?!
魂よ　安らかなれ
People pokoytesy with mirm.
銀仮面はどうした　大きな口をたたきおって
Where the silver mask ?! This because we are pushing here!
それが…
Is he...
ここにいる
I'm here!
貴様　よくもおめおめと帰還できたものだな
You! As you have enough nerve to come back so shamelessly!
聖マヌエル城とやらはイアルダボート神のご加護に恵まれなかったのだろう
Castle of Emmanuel
I do not deserve the blessings Yaldabaoth.
軽々しく神の御名を口にするな
Do not speak so lightly of the Lord!
How are you going to compensate for his failure ?!
此度の失態　どう償うつもりだ
失態？
Failure?
何がおかしい
What's so funny?!
こやつをひっ捕らえよ
Seize him!
You are crazy?
血迷ったか
人払いをしてやったまでだ
Just so we can talk in private.
我が名はヒルメス
My name is Hermes.
父の名はオスロエスという
My father - Osroes.
パルスの先王　オスロエス
The former king of Parsa, Osroes ...
父を殺した簒奪者アンドラゴラスと
Andragoras usurper who killed my father,
その小せがれに思い知らせる必要がある
and his son had to realize,
パルスの正統な王は
that the true king of Parsa am I, Hermes!
この俺　ヒルメスだということをな
貴様
You...
はなから我が国を利用するために…
You from the beginning using my country ...
なぜ素性を明かす気になった
Why suddenly I decided to reveal himself?
お前の真に望むものはなんだ
What do you wish really?
パルスではないだろう
Not Pars after, right?
我らの利害は　いまだ一致しているはず
Our interests can still be aligned.
なるほど　そういうことか
Clear. That's it.
よかろう　パルスの玉座はお主のものだ
Good.
Parsis throne will be yours.
ヒルメス　私をルシタニアの王にできるか
Hermes, you can make me king Lyusitanii?
お望みとあらば　陛下
As you wish, Your Majesty.
もうこっちのは運び終えたぞ
Demolition of everything here.
なんだかもったいないねぇ
Somehow even pity.
残念ながら　ここに残していける兵力はない
Unfortunately, we do not have the strength to leave the people here.
If the bandits make their empty castle lair,
空いた城を盗賊が根城にしては　後々困ることになるのだ
later it will result in a problem.
ねえ　ルシタニアの人たちはどうなるの
Hey, what would happen to lyusitaniantsami?
まさか放り出したり…
Do not throw the same to their own devices?
Our supplies are limited, and the issue of an alarm ...
食料も限られているゆえ　悩ましい問題ではあるが…
It seems the Prince had already decided.
すでに殿下はお決めになっているようだ
大丈夫か
Are you okay?
ありがとう
Thank you.
You do not need thanks. Relax.
礼などいらぬ　安静にな
いってぇ
Painfully!
おっと　落ち着け　ゆっくりやるから
Quietly. I'll be careful.
あ痛ててて
Months and months and months!
動くな　また傷口が開くぞ
Do not move!
And the wounds open again!
Do not jerk!
じっとしていろ
男なら辛抱しろ
You're a man, be patient!
いっ
大丈夫だ　私が必ず皆を故郷に送り届けてやるからな
Everything will be fine.
I'm sure I'll take you to our country.
よし
All!
不器用なヤツ
You're incompetent.
Only you know how to handle a sword?
本当に剣しか扱えないんだな
なんだと
What ?!
貸せ　教えてやる
Come on.
I will teach.
自分から負傷者たちの世話をさせろって　殿下に頼んでついてきたんだろう
You do require to take care of the wounded,
and I asked the Prince to agree, right?
だったら　足手まといになるなよ
Then do not be a burden.
よし
All.
大丈夫か　疲れただろう
Are you okay? Tired?
平気よ　これくらい
Everything is OK.
今　水をくんでくる
I'll get some water.
あの娘　少し変わっているな
This girl is a little different.
娘なのか
It's a girl?
なかなか健気ではないか
Quite gallant.
そうだな
Exactly.
精が出るな　ルシタニアの少女よ
You're all the work, a girl from Lyusitanii.
あまり女扱いするな
Do not treat me like a woman.
慣れぬ
I feel awkward.
お主は進んであいつに仕えていると言ったな
You said that you serve it on their own, right?
うむ
なぜ皆　あのような青二才の王太子に忠実に仕えておるのだ
Why are you so faithfully serve such an inexperienced Crown Prince?
玉座にはそれ自身の意思はない
In the throne there own will.
It's my opinion.
私はこう考えている
座る者によって
Depending on who is sitting on it,
それは正義の椅子にもなるし　悪逆の席にもなる
he may become the seat of justice or cruelty.
神ならぬ人間が政を行う以上　完璧であることもないが
While driving is not a god, but a man,
he can not be perfect.
それに近づこうとする努力を怠れば
But he should not hanker to attain perfection.
誰も止める者がいないままに　王は悪への坂を転げ落ちるであろう
If anyone will not be around,
King will come to the path of evil.
王太子殿下はいつも努力しておられる
Crown Prince always endeavors.
そのことが仕える者の目には明らかなだけなのだ
This fact is obvious to all who serve him.
掛けがえのないお方と思うゆえに
We see how people will relate to it,
皆喜んで仕えておるのじゃ
and happy to serve him.
お主はどうじゃ
And you?
私はお前たちの動きを見張っているだけだ
I'm just following your movements.
せいぜい気をつけろ
Take care of yourself!
何あれ
What was it?
憎ったらしい子だねぇ
Nasty girl.
そうもパルスが嫌いなら　ついてくることなんかないのにさ
If she hates Parsa so I did not go to us.
もう出来るぞ
Soon.
貴様　なんだ
You! What do you want?!
この経典を君に返そうと思って
I thought you back this book.
来い
Come on!
痛てて…
Months and months and months!
王太子のくせに不用心だぞ
You're a prince! And so recklessly behaving!
そうか　いつもこんな感じだが
Yes? I always conduct myself.
何なんだ　この軍は
What's wrong with this army ?!
大切なものをありがとう
Thank you for an important book.
返す必要はない　私がお前を改宗させてやるのだから
You can not return.
I'm going to make you accept our faith.
それはないと思うが
I doubt that happens.
用事はそれだけか
You came just for that ?!
ああ…　手伝えることはあるか
Can I help with anything?
王位継承者だというなら　もっと偉そうにしていろ
Listen, you're the future ruler! Behave more arrogantly!
おお　元気な男の子じゃ
What is a healthy boy.
エトワール様
Lady of the Star.
What? Somewhere hurt?
なんだ　どこか痛いか
抱いてあげて
Hold it.
わ…私が
I-I?
I can not look at it! Child like this keep!
見ちゃいられないね　赤ん坊はこう抱くんだよ
よしよし　もう大丈夫だよ
Quiet, quiet. All is well.
なるほど
Clear.
ほら
Hold.
To her.
いい子だねぇ　きっと立派な盗賊になるよ
Good boy! Become a great bandit.
とんでもない　この子はルシタニアの騎士になるのだ
Well, I do not! He becomes a knight Lyusitanii!
どのような神を信じるのであれ
In whatever gods they may believe
人々の慈しみがこの子の道を照らしますように
may love and compassion will pave the way to the bright child.
随分と長い旅をしてきた感じがする
It seems as if we have done a terribly long way.
ええ　あの日　二人で始めた戦でした
Yes. For us, it all started with the war in the day.
ダリューンよ　思い出に浸るにはまだ随分と早い
Daryun, it is too early to reminisce.
気を抜く暇はないぞ
Do not lose vigilance.
バカを言え　俺の体は常に気合いでみなぎっている
Do not Bring nonsense.
My body is always full of fighting spirit!
殿下　やはりこやつには戦うこと以外ないようですな
Prince,
It looks like he has no other qualities, but to a great warrior.
なんだと
What ?!
そういうお前こそ　戦で策を巡らす以外　何もできないではないか
And you? Besides inventing different military strategies
nothing else do not know how!
私は生まれついての芸術家なのだ
I drew you to the right path!
あれのどこがだ
What are you drawing ?!
耳ある者よ　聞けよかし
If you have ears, listen carefully.
美き国パルスの物語を
This is the tale of the beautiful kingdom of Parsa.
心ある者よ　思いおこし
You, with a pure heart, remember the rule liberator Arslan.
解放王アルスラーンの御代を
見つけてやろうか　殿下のために
Whether to go on a quest?
Prince ...
王位継承の証しとやらを
And prove that he is worthy of the throne.
行くぞ　エクバターナ
Come on! In Ecbatana!
風がざわめき　砕けた気持ち
パルス暦３２１年５月
The era of Parsis, May 321 years.
見透かしてるようで震えたよ
王太子アルスラーン　時に１５歳
Crown Prince Arslan 15 years.
満ちた月の日　遠吠えの命
少年は　そして王となる
And so the guy would be King.
「まだ置いていかないでよ！」
僕ら取り返せるかな　色つきの空
埃まみれの夢舞い上げて　拳を握ったなら
いま走れ　走れ　旋風になって
劣等　絶望　一切吹き飛ばしていく
追いかけなきゃ　最後の扉
何度散ったって　大逆転
この声が嗄れたって　祈りの歌届けたいよ
足りない僕らで信じてた世界を奪うまで
まだまだ　まだまだ　負けられない
僕らは渦の中　まだまだまだ　くたばれない